With this kind of activism, and community investment that typifies the black barbershop, of course the barbershop is a perfect place to talk about high blood pressure and other health concerns in the community. First, the barbershop is not a medical setting, and so it doesn't have all the negative psychological baggage that comes along with that. When you're in a barbershop, you're in your territory, and you're among friends who share your history, your struggle and your health risks. Second, because the barbershop is a place of connection, loyalty and trust, it's a place where you're more open to have a conversation about health and especially about high blood pressure. After all, conversations about high blood pressure have all the elements of great shop talk: stress and high blood pressure, food and high blood pressure, relationships and high blood pressure, and yes, what it's like to be a black man in America and high blood pressure. But you can do more than just talk about high blood pressure in the barbershop. You can concretely take action. Here we have an opportunity to partner with the Denny Moe's of the world and empower communities to address the health inequities that uniquely affect it. When high blood pressure screening expanded from clinics and hospitals to communities in the 1960s and '70s, black physicians like Dr. Eli Saunders in Baltimore and Dr. Keith Ferdinand in New Orleans were at the forefront of bringing health promotion to community hubs in urban black neighborhoods. These pioneers paved the way for my professional journey with barbershops and health, which began in Chicago in medical school. The very first research project that I worked on as a medical student was to help design healthcare interventions that would appeal to black men. We conducted about a dozen focus groups with a broad cross-section of black men, and we learned that for them, being healthy was as much about being perceived as healthy as it was about feeling healthy, and that feeling good went hand in hand with looking good. This work led to the development of Project Brotherhood, a community clinic founded by Dr. Eric Whitaker that provided tailored healthcare to black men. Part of this tailored care involved having a barber on the premises to reward the men who came for needed healthcare with a free haircut, to let the men know that we, too, valued how they looked as well as how they felt, and that what was important to them was also important to us. But while there's only one Project Brotherhood, there are thousands of black barbershops where the intersection of health and haircuts can be cultivated. The next stop on my journey was Dallas, Texas, where we learned that barbers were not only willing but fully able to roll up their sleeves and participate in delivering needed health services to improve the health of their customers and their community. We teamed up with an amazing cadre of black barbers and taught them how to measure blood pressure and how to counsel their customers and refer them to doctors to help manage high blood pressure. The barbers were not only willing to do it but they were damn good at it. Over a three-year period, the barbers measured thousands of blood pressures resulting in hundreds of black men being referred to doctors for medical care of their high blood pressure. These barber-doctor partnerships resulted in a 20 percent increase in the number of men who were able to achieve target blood pressure levels and a three-point drop, on average, in the blood pressure of each participant. If we were to extrapolate that three point drop to every single black man with high blood pressure in America, we would prevent 800 heart attacks, 500 strokes and 900 deaths from high blood pressure in just one year. And our experience with barbershops has been no different in New York City, where my journey has currently led me. With an incredible team of diverse research assistants, community health workers and volunteers, we've been able to partner with over 200 barbershops and other trusted community venues to reach over 7,000 older black men. And we've offered high blood pressure screening and counseling to each and every one of them. Thanks to Denny Moe and the myriad other barbers and community leaders who shared the vision of opportunity and empowerment to make a difference in their communities, we've been able to not only lower blood pressure in our participants, but we've also been able to impact other health indicators. So what do you see? What is your barbershop? Where is that place for you where people who are affected by a unique problem can meet a unique solution? When you find that place, see the opportunity. Thank you. (Applause)
Con este tipo de activismo, y la inversión en la comunidad que caracteriza a la peluquería negra, por supuesto, la peluquería es un lugar perfecto para hablar de presión arterial alta y otros problemas de salud en la comunidad. En primer lugar, la peluquería no es un entorno médico, y por tanto no tiene todo ese bagaje psicológico negativo asociado a eso. Cuando estás en una barbería, uno está en su propio territorio, y está entre amigos con quien compartir su historia, su lucha y sus riesgos para la salud. En segundo lugar, como la peluquería es un lugar de conexión, lealtad y confianza, es un lugar donde uno está más abierto a conversar sobre salud y sobre todo sobre presión arterial alta. Después de todo, las conversaciones sobre presión arterial alta tienen todos los elementos de una buena charla: estrés y presión arterial alta, alimentación y presión arterial alta, relaciones y presión arterial alta, y sí, lo que se siente siendo un hombre negro en EE.UU. y la presión arterial alta. Pero se puede hacer más que tan solo hablar de la presión arterial alta en la peluquería. Uno puede tomar medidas concretas. Aquí tenemos la oportunidad de asociarnos con el Denny Moe del mundo y dar autonomía a las comunidades para hacer frente a las desigualdades en salud que afectan de manera particular. Cuando la comunidad de la exploración de la presión arterial alta de las clínicas y hospitales a las comunidades en la década del 60 y 70, los médicos negros como el Dr. Eli Saunders en Baltimore y el Dr. Keith Ferdinand en Nueva Orleans estaban en la vanguardia en la promoción de la salud llevando centros comunitarios a los barrios negros urbanos. Estos pioneros abrieron el camino a mi trayectoria profesional con las barberías y la salud, que comenzó en Chicago en la facultad de medicina. En el 1er proyecto de investigación en el que trabajé siendo estudiante de medicina ayudaba a diseñar intervenciones para el cuidado de la salud que atrajeran a los hombres negros. Hemos dirigido unos 12 grupos con una amplia muestra representativa de hombres negros, y aprendimos que para ellos estar sano era ser percibido como saludable. Como si sentirse saludable, y esa buena sensación fuesen mano a mano con un buen aspecto. Este trabajo condujo el desarrollo del Proyecto Hermandad, una clínica de la comunidad fundada por el Dr. Eric Whitaker que daba asistencia sanitaria personalizada a hombres negros. Parte de esta atención personalizada implicaba tener un peluquero en las instalaciones para recompensar a los hombres que vinieran a la asistencia sanitaria con un corte de pelo gratis. Hacer que los hombres supieran que nosotros también valoramos el aspecto, así como también cómo se sentían, y que lo que era importante para ellos también lo era para nosotros. Sin embargo, mientras que solo hay un Proyecto Hermandad, hay miles de peluquerías para hombres negros donde la intersección de la salud y cortes de pelo puede ser cultivada. La siguiente parada de mi viaje era de Dallas, Texas, donde aprendimos que los barberos no solo estaban dispuestos sino que eran totalmente capaces de arremangarse y participar en la prestación de servicios de salud para mejorar la salud de sus clientes y su comunidad. Nos asociamos con un increíble grupo de peluqueros negros y se les enseñó a medir la presión arterial y a aconsejar a sus clientes y remitirlos a los médicos para ayudar a controlar la presión arterial alta. Los barberos no solo estaban dispuestos a hacerlo sino que eran muy buenos haciéndolo. Durante un período de tres años, los barberos tomaron miles de presiones arteriales dando como resultado que cientos de hombres negros fueron a los médicos para la atención médica por su presión arterial alta. Estas asociaciones barbero-médico han dado lugar a un aumento del 20 % en el número de hombres capaces de alcanzar los niveles objetivo de presión arterial y una caída de tres puntos, en promedio, en la presión sanguínea de cada participante. Si extrapoláramos la caída de tres puntos a cada hombre negro solo con presión arterial alta en EE.UU. evitaríamos 800 ataques cardíacos, 500 accidentes cerebrovasculares y 900 muertes por presión arterial alta en solo un año. Y nuestra experiencia con las peluquerías no ha sido diferente en la ciudad de Nueva York, a donde recientemente mi viaje me ha llevado. Con un equipo increíble de diversos asistentes en la investigación, los trabajadores de salud comunitarios y voluntarios, hemos podido asociarnos con más de 200 peluquerías y otros lugares de confianza para la comunidad para llegar a más de 7000 hombres mayores negros. Y hemos ofrecido evaluaciones de presión arterial alta y asesoramiento a todos y cada uno de ellos. Gracias a Denny Moe y a la miríada de otros barberos y líderes de la comunidad que compartieron la visión de oportunidades y el empoderamiento para hacer una diferencia en sus comunidades, no solo hemos logrado reducir la presión arterial en nuestros participantes, sino también hemos mejorado otros indicadores de salud. Entonces, ¿qué es lo que ven? ¿Cuál es su barbería? ¿Dónde está ese lugar para Ud. donde las personas afectadas por un problema único pueden obtener una solución única? Cuando encuentren ese lugar, tengan en cuenta esa oportunidad. Gracias. (Aplausos)